<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datt Dongare | Technical Director at BTW Group</title>
    <description>Datt Dongare is Technical Director at BTW Group. I&#39;m an entreprenuer, programmer, analyst and a digital marketer.</description>
    <link>http://dattdongare.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dattdongare.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 20:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 20:51:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Is Better For You Startup or MNC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays people find a startup in every corner. Whether a person is experienced or a fresher, it’s hard for him to choose between a startup and an MNC. Why it shouldn’t be hard, even if it is a critical decision for your further career.
I have listed below a little information in regard to comparison in both startup and MNC’s which will let you decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Skill Development:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will develop more skills within a shorter span of time. Not just technical skills but the experiences which will help you throughout your life such as dedication, teamwork, time management, cost management etc. This is important, after all, your skills will help you grow faster in your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skill development graph is much moderate than startups. Sometimes you won’t develop skill at all for certain period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me share an experience of my friend.
One of my friends got joining in reputed MNC and after 9 months of his working, the company made him sit on the bench for 2 years, also later while switching to another company he faced many difficulties due to lack of skills he could not develop in those years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Work and Job Satisfaction:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to work harder, company’s growth depends on every team member, you may need to spend more hours at the office. But at the end of the day you’ll be satisfied with your job and surely you will constantly learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your work will have fix time, let’s say 9 am to 5 pm. Your job satisfaction will depend on the type of project you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Growth/ Opportunities:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated earlier you grow fast in terms of skills &amp;amp; knowledge. Another perk you have is getting extra opportunities to get leading position/designation in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At MNC you might need to wait years to be in a higher position as most of the company determine your role based on your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Salary:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll get less salary in a startup, but it can provide more salary when it starts growing further you might get shares in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may get a higher salary in MNC related to startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Politics/ Transparency:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have more value in the company as a person. There is more transparency, you directly works with the founding members of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MNCs are less transparent, people involve in politics to grow which might drag you down even if you’re deserving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Facilities:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Startup:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to work in a small place with fewer amenities/facilities, maybe a room or co-working space. It might not have facilities like recreation hall or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;MNC:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the MNCs have big and deluxe offices with many facilities like a pantry, sports spaces and other privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends on what do you want in your world currently, If you want reclining job with more salary in hand, MNC is best for you. If you are ready to work harder &amp;amp; learning faster in a small team, a startup is great.
In my opinion, it’s good to have some struggle while building a company, making it bigger which gives more job satisfaction rather than doing same work daily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 19:16:52 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://dattdongare.com/blog/startup-or-mnc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dattdongare.com/blog/startup-or-mnc/</guid>
        
        <category>startups</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneur</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
